# Guilherme Patriota

C++ Developer



H4V 2Y2 Montreal/QC



+1 (438) 926-0872



linkedin.com/in/guilhermepatriota



gdp.ai.data.eng@gmail.com

# About me -

Passionate about technology and software Development, I am an experienced developer with a strong background in electronics and telecommunications, as well as a master's degree in electrical engineering. Since 2016, I have been a software engineering and computer engineering professor at UNINTER in Brazil, where I created a practical activity system with real-world cases from the job market for all IT courses. I am currently looking for new professional opportunities in my areas of interest.

# Skills -

Programming, C++, C, Python

Electronics, IoT, MQTT

Kafka, Constrained Devices

Statistical Analysis, AI

Big Data, Hadoop, Spark

Database, SQL, NoSQL

Machine Learning, NLP

#### English\*5 French\*5 Portuguese\*6

(\*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

## Portfolio -



### Experience

UNIVERSITY PROFESSOR, UNINTER and FAESP, Brazil

since 2016

- Courses: Embedded Systems, Electronics, C and Python Programming, System Analysis, Big Data, Natural Language Processing, Databases, NoSQL, Artificial Intelligence.

\* **Achievement:** Created a system of practical activities with real cases from the job market for all IT courses (Big Data, NoSQL and Python).

C++ DEVELOPER, Boa Impressão 3D, Brazil

2020-2021

- Developing electronics and software for new equipment.
- Managing the assembly line.
- $\star$  **Achievement:** Creation of a high-capacity 3D printer (C/C++).
- \* **Achievement:** Implementation of a production line control and maintenance system based on Key Performance Indicators (KPIs) with Python.

#### 3D PRINTER TECHNICIAN, GS3D, Brazil

2018-2020

- Building, repairing, and configuring 3D printers.
- Conducting 3D modeling and research on healthcare projects.
- \* **Achievement:** Creation of a company focused on meeting hospital needs.

#### MEDICAL EQUIPMENT ENGINEER, Hospitals in Brazil

2012-2018

- Maintaining and repairing medical equipment.
- Managing teams of technicians.
- \* **Achievement:** Creation of a project management department based on PMBOK.
- \* **Achievement:** Implementation of a clinical engineering and medical equipment traceability department with management software on React platform (Javascript).

### Education

SPECIALIZATION IN ONLINE LEARNING, UNINTER, Brazil Online pedagogy, flipped classroom, and other learning techniques.	2022
MBA IN HEALTHCARE, FGV, Brazil Improvements in healthcare service management.	2016
M.SC. IN ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING, UFPR, Brazil Applied AI to electronics and telecommunications.	2011
<b>B.SC. IN ELECTRONIC ENGINEERING</b> , UFPR/ENSPS, Brazil/France Sandwich degree in electronic engineering and telecommunications.	2006

### **Additional Training**

KNOWLEDGE DISCOVERY IN DATABASES AND DATA MINING, UFPR, Brazil	2020
FOUNDATIONS OF DATA SCIENCE, Aldeia Coworking, Brazil	2020
INTRODUCTION TO PYTHON PROGRAMMING, MITX, USA	2020
FUNDAMENTALS OF AI, Data Science Academy, Brazil	2020
DATASCIENCE 2.0, Data Science Academy, Brazil	2020

### Volunteer Experience

#### 3D PRINTER TECHNICIAN, GS3D, Brazil

2020

Development, 3D printing, and delivery of 500 visors for donation to healthcare professionals during the first 6 months of the COVID-19 pandemic.

#### **Hobbies and Interests**

- Professional: Teaching, AI, Blockchain, 3D Printing, Research. - Personal: Dance, Scouting

\*References available upon request